# **TABITHA TOWNES**

707-592-6297 tabithatownes@gmail.com

2223 Dodge St, Apt 1509 Omaha, NE 68102



https://www.linkedin.com/in/tabitha-townes-77a64248/



https://github.com/ TMTownes

#### **PROFILE**

I am a creative, career-changing Java Full Stack Developer with a background in building exciting programs to meet specified requirements. My unique personal and professional experience, both domestic and abroad, contributes to my goal-oriented approach to programming and project development. Contributing to my success, is my tenacious curiosity and self-starter attitude.

#### **SKILLS**

- ReactJs
- JavaScript
- PostrgesSQL
- TypeScript
- R Studios
- Python
- Microsoft Suites

- Business Intelligence
- Complex Problem Solving
- Presentation Development
- Professional Communication
- Procedural Compliance
- · Interpersonal Interviewing
- Intermediate Spanish

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Associate Developer, Revature; Remote — Jun 2022-Oct 2022

Built a complete Java web API using MVC and Front Controller design patterns. Generated PostgresSQL AWS RDS with DBeaver interface. Created dynamic React web applications with mobile flexibility and map functions. Organized Agile Scrum, DevOps services, and REST frameworks.

# Human Services Specialist, County of San Diego, CA — Jan 2020-Jun 2022

Conducted client interviews to obtain and verify PINs for public assistance services. Analyzed government applications to determine eligibility.

Managed caseloads and generated reports for ongoing cases.

## UI/UX Designer, Imagine The Stage (ITS) — Sep 2019-Jun 2020

Designed frontend web frameworks and communicated with stakeholders to implement product visual and functional requirements. Verified program logic using testing and debugging best practices.

## Robotics Educator, Sacred Heart School; Barcelona, Spain — 2016-2019

Developed educational STEM program for coding and elementary physics. Monitored key performance indicators for multiple student classes. Instructed in basic robot design, programming, and testing.

# **EDUCATION**

University of California, Davis — International Relations, B.S. 2012